翻译/时间轴校准:CharlesChouBlues
America has produced only three classic writers,
从古至今，美国仅仅出产了三位一流作家：
Mark Twain, J.D. Salinger,and me.
马克・吐温，J.D.塞林格和我
（注：J.D.塞林格，代表作为《麦田里的守望者》）
I'm Jonathan Flynn.
我是乔纳桑・弗林
Everything I write is a masterpiece.
我书写的一切皆为杰作
And soon, very soon,
很快，无需时日
I shall be known.
我将为世人所知
At this point of the story,let's call it the present,
在故事的现阶段――我们可称其为“当下”
I am an upstanding citizen of these United States.
我是一名正直的美国公民
I have a job,
我有一份工作
a roof over my head.I have sustenance.
一处栖身之所，三餐足以果腹
Perhaps I'll let you read my masterpiece someday.
也许在未来的某天你们能读到我的大作
The Button Man, also known as The Confessions of Christopher Cobb.
《纽扣人》，它还有另一个名字叫《克里斯托弗・科布的自白书》
It's classic.
绝对一流
This isn't his story.
这不是他的故事
Well, it is,but he is not telling it,
好吧，其实就是，但故事的叙述者并不是他
I am.
而是我
I'm Nick Flynn, his son, and I am sort of trying to be a writer.
我是尼克・弗林，他的儿子，我可以说是正在尝试成为一名作家
I mean, not at this very moment.
我的意思是现在不行
At this moment I'm trying to...
现在我正试着...
Wake up.
起来
Hey, wake up.
喂，起来
All my life, my father has been manifest as an absence.
在我人生的旅程里，父亲曾一度以一张空座的形式出现
A non-presence.A name without a body.
他是缺席者，是一个没有实体的名字
What if he doesn't show up?
他要是不出现该怎么办？
He's gonna show up.
他会的
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Because if he doesn't show up this time,
因为如果他这次再不现身的话
I'm going to kill him.
我就宰了他
How will you find him to kill him?
那你要怎么把他找出来宰了？
I have ways.
我自有办法
Can we get ice cream if he doesn't show up?
如果他不出现的话，我们能去买冰淇淋么？
Here is the bus.Here he is.
巴士来了，他来了
No, that is not him.
不对，那不是他
He must be in the back.
他肯定在后面的座位上
What kind of ice cream do you want to get?
冰淇淋要什么味道的？
Chocolate.
巧克力味
Some part of me knew he would show up someday.
某个部分的我清楚他总有一天会现身的
If I stayed in one place long enough, he would find me,
如果我在一个地方呆得足够久，他就会找到我
like you are taught to do when you are lost.
某个人曾告诉过你，走失的时候应该这么做，对吧
But what do you do if both of you are lost
可要是你和某个人都迷了路
and you both end up in the same place, waiting
你们来到同一个地方，同时开始了漫长的等待，又该如何是好
Hey, sweetie.
嘿，小甜心
Hey.
嘿
I'm exhausted.
我快累死了
How was your flight?
飞得怎么样？
Non-stop turbulence.
颠个不停
Nick, what is the ashtray doing by the bed?
烟灰缸怎么在床头柜上？
Sorry.
不好意思
Lipstick?
唇膏？
You are a fucking asshole.
你这个混蛋
Look, you are the one who said you didn't see a future for us.
是你说在我们俩身上看不到未来的
I wonder why? This is yours!
我想知道为什么？这是你的！
This is yours.
你的！
And this is yours! - All right.
你的！ - 好啦
And this is yours. All right.
还是你的。 - 好啦
My book. And Yeats.
别这么对我的书。- 叶芝
（注：威廉・巴特勒・叶芝，爱尔兰诗人，剧作家）
Oh, more Yeats.All right.
又一本叶芝 - 够了
Wow! You are so well-read.
哇，你可真是博览群书啊
All right.All right!
够了，够了！
I'll pay for the mirror.
我会赔你镜子钱的
As soon as I get a job.
我找到工作马上赔你
Sorry.
不好意思
For what, your complete inadequacy as a human being?
不好意思什么，觉得自己不配做人？
Yes.
是
Well, you warned me.
你这倒是点醒我了
Don't worry, you're back.
别担心，你又回来了
Hello.
你好呀
Back in the hands of a master storyteller.
回到了故事大师的手上
Yeah, yeah,go fuck yourself.
呵呵，去你的吧
I like kids and small animals.
我喜欢孩子和小动物
What I don't like is queers and blacks
但我不喜欢那些成天盯着你屁眼的
who try and fuck you up the ass all day and all night.
基佬和黑鬼
（注：fuck up the ass根据停顿不同既可指惹怒某人，又能描述同性恋者的性爱方式）
But more on that later.
关于这点，我们稍后详谈
What I am, always have been, is an artist.
我是一名艺术家
Shut the fuck up.
他妈的给我安静点
Shut up. Shut up.
安静！安静！
Shut the fuck up! Shut up!
你大爷的给我安静点！闭嘴！
Shut up!
闭嘴！
A friend of a friend knew a couple of guys
我一个朋友的朋友认识几个人
who were renting an entire building,
他们出租一整栋楼
a former strip joint called "Good Times."
那里原本是名为“好时光”的脱衣舞酒吧
Unfortunately, the good times were not had by all,
不幸的是，并非所有人都有段好时光
like that Harvard student who was found
就像三年前
stabbed to death in the doorway three years before.
在这道门前被捅死的那个哈佛学生一样
I don't know what to tell you.
我不知道该跟你说什么
That's something you got to figure out, man.
你自己想想该说什么，老兄
So, what appeals to you about living here?
所以，吸引你住在这里的是哪一点？
Low rent. Yeah, hold on one second.
房租低。 - 你稍等
Do you have a job?
你有工作么？
Uh, no. I have some money saved up.
呃，没有。我有一些存款
I was working as an electrician,
我以前是个电工
but now I'm looking for a new line of work.
不过现在我在找别的工作
An electrician?
电工？
Can you wire this place up to look like a spaceship?
你能把这里改造成宇宙飞船内部么
Ivan. - Yes.
埃文  - 行啊
And what field of employment are you interested in?
你对哪个领域感兴趣？
Something different,something more meaningful.
一些与众不同的，更有意义的
"More meaningful," what does that mean?
什么是“更有意义的”
I don't know.
不知道
Are those, like,the names of strippers?
那些是脱衣舞娘的名字么？
Yeah. The landlord's Mafia, so he
just left all this shit the way it was
嗯，这里曾经是黑手党的地盘
when the FBI shut him down.
所以FBI的人把这里查封以后里面的装潢都没动过
Any family?
有家人么？
Stop interrogating the guy.
别像警察侦讯似的好不
I'm sorry, Ivan, but my last roommate had
不好意思，埃文，可是我上一个室友
his entire family from Cambodia sleeping in the living room.
把他柬埔寨的家人全接到客厅来了
No, my mom's dead, and my dad, I haven't heard from in 18 years, so...
没有，我母亲已经过世了，我的父亲已经消失了18年，所以...
Perfect.Done.
完美，你可以搬进来了
So, are you guys like...
你俩是不是有啥（JQ）...
No. No. Okay.
没。没。 - 好吧
So, Denise, didn't you say they were hiring people at your work?
蒂尼斯，你不是说过你们那招人么？
They usually are.
他们一直在招人
Good. 'Cause I think Nick here is looking for a job.
很好，尼克他正在找工作呢
Give him a break, man. Where do you work?
让他说。 - 你在哪工作？
Harbor Street Inn. You heard of it?
港湾街旅店。听过么？
No. - It's a homeless shelter.
没有。 - 是个流浪汉收容所。
That sounds intense. So are you like a do-gooder?
听起来很辛苦。 所以你是个社会改良家？
（注：do-gooder带着玩笑语气，多指一腔热血但好心办坏事的社会志愿者）
No, I'm a do-badder,but I work at Harbor Street.
不，我是个社会破坏者，但我在港湾街上班。
（注：do-badder是个生造词，相对于do-gooder，指坏心办好事）
What makes you a do-badder?
是什么让你做这一行的？
I bet you would like to know.
你来了就知道了。
I would.
成
Upon occasion, rare occasion, but still,
偶尔，数量极少但仍可能发生的情况下
I'll pick up a female fare and we will strike up a conversation.
我会拉上一个能和我“促膝长谈”的女客人
Oh, Jonathan.
哦，乔纳桑
哦
Jonathan.
乔纳桑
Yeah.
嗯
Let's be a little realistic here.
咱们现实点吧
All right.
行啊
Still, we are having fun,aren't we, Buttercup?
不过我们玩得挺开心的，不是么，小金花？
Absolutely.
当然了
Who is this?
这是谁？
That is my wife and kid.
我的老婆孩子
Will you listen to this shit.
你要听我废话一番么？
You are married?
你结婚了？
Divorced,a long time ago.
离了，很久以前的事了
Well, I had better get you home.
好了，我现在送你回家
I left the meter running. That'll be $240.
车还打着表呢，现在估计跳到240刀了
Quiet!
安静！
安静点！
I can't even think anymore!
我都没法思考了！
Excuse me.
等我一下
Open up!
开门！
Asshole.
混球
Hey.
嘿
I was hoping you'd be here.
我一直在等你来这呢
Why is that?
为什么？
Well, so I know somebody.
这样就有个熟人作伴了
We don't exactly know each other, do we?
我们不算熟人吧？
I guess not.
我猜也不是
I'm not interested in a relationship.
我对交往没什么兴趣
What?
什么？
I'm not interested in a relationship.
我不打算当你的女朋友
Okay, I can cope.
好吧，我能应付得来
Okay.
好吧
Phone call.
电话
Who is it?
谁啊？
Your father.
你爸
Who?
谁？
Your father, who you supposedly hadn't seen in 18 years.
你爸，那个你本该已经18年没见过他人影的
This is Nick.
我是尼克
Is this Nicholas Flynn?
是尼古拉斯・弗林么？
Yes.
是
Nicholas, this is your father, Jonathan Flynn.
尼古拉斯，我是你爹，乔纳桑・弗林
It is?
真的？
It is. I have a question for you.
真的，我问你个问题
Do you have a truck? A pickup truck?
你有卡车么，载货的那种
Yeah, as a matter of fact, I do.
对，事实上，我确实有一辆
I heard as much.
我听说过
From who?
谁说的？
Your grandmother, she mentioned it a few years ago.
你祖母说的，她几年前提到过
You do remember your grandmother, don't you?
你还记得她吧？
I do. - Good.
记得 - 很好
Now I want you to get in your truck and drive over here.
现在我要你开车过来
I'm sorry, you say you are my father?
不好意思，你说你是我爸？
That is correct.
正确
I was evicted and I need you to get over here
我被赶出来了，我需要你过来帮我
and help me move my stuff, Nicholas.
把我的东西搬走，尼古拉斯
How did you get this number?
你怎么知道这里的电话的？
Information. Now listen to me carefully.
信息台。现在仔细听我说
I am sitting behind a door with a shotgun.
我正拿着一杆猎枪坐在一扇门后头
I'm waiting for the knob to turn.
就等着门把手的动静呢
Get over here right now.
你马上过来
That is an appealing offer.
还真是迫切需求啊
You are damn right it is.
没错，是非常迫切
It's all yours. You are my sole heir, Nicholas.
这些都是你东西，你是我唯一的子嗣，尼古拉斯
I want you to have everything.
我希望你能继承它们
You have a pen or a pencil?
手边有笔么？
Because I want you to write this address down.
把我说的地址记下来
What am I doing here?
我到底是来干嘛的？
What are you doing here? What are we doing here?
你来这干嘛的？我们来这干嘛的？
Thanks for coming.
谢谢你们陪我过来
Sure. Should we just wait here? Or do you want us...
我们要在这里等还是...？
Who is it?
是谁？
It's Nick. Nicholas.
是我，尼克。尼古拉斯
Come on in, the door is open. Come in.
进来，门开着，进来
I'll be with you in a minute.
等我一分钟
I appreciate you coming over, Nicholas.
很感谢你过来，尼古拉斯
We're put on this Earth to help other people.
我们存在世间的意义就是帮助他人
Yeah.
嗯
We were put on this Earth to help other people, Nicholas.
我们存在世间的意义就是帮助他人， 尼古拉斯
I regret our mutual loss.
我对我们彼此错过的一切感到遗憾
I am a born writer,so are you.
我是一个天生的作家，你也一样
Get this in your head at once. I am a classic storyteller. A great writer.
现在立刻记住这句话。我是一个一流的叙事者。一个伟大的作家。
I think I want to be a writer.
我想我希望成为一个作家。
Yeah?
所以？
Dad is a writer, right?
老爸是个作家，对不对？
Ha!
哈！
What makes you think that?
你怎么突然想到这个？
It says right here. It says,"Work on my novel is going well.
信里说：“我的小说进展顺利。”
"I shall soon win the Nobel Prize
“我很快就会得诺贝尔奖
"for both storytelling and poetry.
“不管是小说还是诗作
"No fear."
“别担心。”
You know where that letter was written from?
你知道他是在哪写的这封信么？
Prison. - Mmm-hmm.
监狱里 - 嗯哼
Why is he in prison again?
他怎么又进监狱了？
Interstate transportation of stolen securities.
跨洲运送窃取所得有价证券罪
What is that?
什么意思？
He cashed forged checks.
他拿伪造的支票兑现
He stole thousands and thousands of dollars.
相当于是偷了很多很多的钱
Do you know how much of that we have seen?
你知道他分给我们多少么？
Zero. Zilch.
零。 - 半点没有
Zippo. Nothing.
什么都没有
Nada. Niente.
没有什么 - 啥都没有
（注：此处有点类似于联想游戏，说出尽可能多个首字母相同且意思相近的单词）
Have you seen my baseball glove?
看到我的棒球手套没？
If it were up your ass,you would know where it was.
如果它就贴在你屁股上的话，你肯定找得着
（注：up your ass意为“不关我事”，同时有“在你屁股上”的意思）
Well? Gonna come in?
准备进来么？
Pleasure to see you, Nicholas,aside from the circumstances.
真高兴看到你，尼古拉斯，但我真不待见这地了
What are the circumstances?
怎么了？
The circumstances are
现在的情况是
that I had a disagreement with my scum-sucking landlord.
我跟那垃圾房东闹翻了
I don't know why.
然后不知道怎么回事
And so he decided to bring the police into the discussion.
他决定让警察介入
So now I'm forced to move.
于是我不得不搬走
Move where?
搬去哪里？
I'm considering my options.I'm a sought-after house guest.
我还在选呢。一堆人请我到他们家去。
You know why?
知道这是为什么？
No.
不知道
Because I'm an excellent raconteur.
因为我是一个极好的说书人
But until I find a new place,
但在我找到新的居所之前
I have to put all my things in storage.
我得把所有的东西都放在这儿
Hey. So I'm not bringing the gun in my truck.
嘿，所以我不用把那枪拿上卡车了吧
What? - The shotgun.
什么? - 那把猎枪啊
Shotgun?
猎枪？
Uh, yeah. You said you had a shotgun.
呃，是啊。你说你有把猎枪
A shotgun? Who said that? I abhor firearms.
猎枪？谁说的？我是反火器主义者
I mean, don't get me wrong, I can defend myself.
我是说，你别误会了，我可以保护我自己
Let me just...
你看...
You see this? - Yes.
看到没？ - 嗯
Anyone messes with me when I'm driving
要是在我开车或者走路或者做别的事的时候
or walking down the street, whatever.
有人敢找我麻烦
Bamo! Right in the head. It sends a little message, let me tell you.
砰！直接砸他们一脑瓜子。我跟你说
I'd like to take that scumbag landlord，
我现在真想去找那个人渣房东
and I'd like to ram it right up his ass.
直接把这个抡到他屁股上去
This landlord, this merchant, this fucking user...
这个房东，奸商，操蛋的
Hey, that is great. Would you mind putting that away?
好啦，说得很对，你能把这个拿远点么？
I'd like to take this and...
我要把这个...
Please? ...ram it up his fucking ass,
能请你...？ ...一下抡到他的屁股上去，
twist it around,pull it down,
转几圈，再拉个口子
rip out his innards and fucking pull them out.
把他的内脏全掏出来
You get the fucking picture.
你能想象这样的画面么？
That was my first wife, Jody.
这是我第一任妻子，朱迪
I know who it is.She was my mother.
我知道她是谁，她是我妈
I know she was your mother.
我知道她是你妈
She was the most beautiful woman in the world.
她是世界上最美的女人
She was the love of my life.
她是我命中挚爱
She was the light of my love.
爱情之光
I know if she was still alive today, we'd be together.
如果她现在还活着，我们会重归于好的
Such a tragic accident.
真是个不幸的意外
What accident?
什么意外？
The accident that cut her life short.
缩短她的生命的那个
It wasn't an accident. She left a note.
那不是意外。她留了张纸条
Did it mention me?
里头提到我了么？
No.
没有
Ah.
哦
Not much of a letter writer, your mother.
你妈她不太会写信
All right, Nicholas. Why don't we get started.
好啦，尼古拉斯，咱们为何不开始干活呢
You can just take all this stuff and throw it in a box.
你只需要把这些东西拿起来丢进箱子里
The paintings,be careful of.
对这些画小心点
Especially this one and that
one, and that one on the wall.
特别是这幅还有那幅，还有墙上的那幅
Be careful of all this stuff. It's all valuable.
小心点拿这些东西，都很贵重
Nicholas, I want you to have this.
尼古拉斯，你拿着这个
This is an original Jackson Pollock.
杰克森・波洛克的真迹
（注：杰克森・波洛克，美国滴画大师，抽象表现主义代表人）
He was a friend.
我的老朋友
Oh, no. I couldn't.
哦，不，我不能拿
No, I want you to have it.
不，你拿着
Okay, thanks.
好吧，谢谢
Are you going to help move this stuff, since it's yours?
你要帮我搬这些东西么，全是你的
I wish I could, but I suffer from lethal phlebitis in both legs.
我也想啊，但是我两腿都得了要老命的静脉炎
You be careful with those boxes. There's manuscripts.
你小心点拿，这些可都是原稿
Manuscripts.
原稿
Those are your friends?
他们是你朋友？
I guess. Yeah.
大概吧
A homosexual and a black pothead?
一个基佬和一个吸大麻的黑鬼？
Well, good luck to you.
祝你好运
Well, I have to get to work now.
我得去上班了
Do you mind just locking the padlock when you're finished?
不介意搬完之后帮我把挂锁都锁上吧？
Yeah. Wait. So you drive a taxi?
当然。等下，你是开出租车的?
Well, it's an excellent way of learning
这是了解不同人群的
about all different kinds of people.
最佳手段
And what is your vocation?
你做什么工作？
My vocation? Uh...
我的工作？呃...
I've done lots of different jobs.
我做过很多种不同的工作
I always thought you'd end up a writer, like your old man.
我一直觉得你会像自己的老爹一样成为一名作家
Actually, I do write. You know, sometimes. I try.
事实上，我确实有写作。我有时会自己尝试去写
Well, there is no such thing as trying to write.
没有“尝试写作”这一回事
One writes,or one doesn't.
只有“写”或者“不写”，就这么简单
You have to take every opportunity to practice your craft.
你需要把握每一个练笔的机会
Anyway, I know you have inherited some writing talent from me,
不管怎么说，我知道你从我这继承了写作的才能
because I am a truly great writer.
因为我是一个真正伟大的作家
I'm going to show you something.
给你看点东西
I have a letter from Viking Press.
我这有封维京出版社的信
You've heard of Viking Press, haven't you?
你听过这个出版社吧
Yeah.
嗯
Look at this. Look at that phrase there.
看这个。看这句话
"Your book is a virtuoso display of personality.
“贵书实乃社会百态的精湛陈列
"Unfortunately, its dosage would kill hardier readers than we have here."
“不幸的是，其精湛之剂量远超我社读者的承受范围。”
"Virtuoso display," Viking Press.
“精湛陈列”，维京出版社
Well, it's been a great pleasure, Nicholas.
我很高兴，尼古拉斯
Well, hey, uh...
呃，嘿
All right.
好吧
You need anything? Aside from the Pollock?
你还要什么么？除了波洛克？
No.
不
All right. Well, au revoir, then.
好吧，再见（法语）
You're welcome.
很高兴为您服务
Don't mention it.
别客气
Your father's a nightmare.
你老爸真是难搞
What's that?
那是什么
It's a fucking Jackson Pollock painting.
是幅该死的杰克森・波洛克画作
Jackson Pollock? Jesus!
杰克森・波洛克？老天啊！
Hmm.
嗯
Pollock spelled his name wrong when he signed it.
波洛克签名的时候都拼错了
So then he gives me a gift,
然后他就给了我一个礼物
a Jackson Pollock painting.
一副杰克森・波洛克的画
Which, like an asshole, I think is real.
我得像个傻瓜一样把它当成是真的
So after 18 years of wondering,
所以在好奇了18年之后
here's what I learned about my father.
老爸终于让我明白了一件事
He's a racist, he's a homophobe, and he's fucking crazy.
他是个种族主义者，恐同者，还他妈的是个疯子
Can you reach him? I mean, if you wanted to?
你能联系到他么？如果你想联系他的话？
I don't know that I ever want to see him again. Really.
说真的，我不知道自己是不是还想再见到他
I don't know how I feel about it.
我不知道自己的感觉是什么样的
I can't really locate what I feel.
我不确定自己现在的感觉是什么
Is that why you called me?
你打电话给我就为了这个？
To help you locate your feelings?
帮你确定下感觉？
Do you want to get out of here? You look beautiful.
要出去玩玩么？你看起来很美
None of that. We're friends now.
不用了。我们现在是朋友
We're friends?
我们是朋友？
Yeah.
嗯
I mean, don't get me wrong, I enjoyed sleeping with you, but...
别误会，我觉得那天晚上很愉快，不过...
Thank you.
谢谢
I told you I didn't want a relationship.
我说过我不想确定关系
So, now we're friends.
所以我们现在是朋友
Okay. Well, thanks for letting me know.
好吧，谢谢你告诉我
You're welcome.
不客气
You should think about working at Harbor Street.
你应该考虑下来海湾街工作
Why?
为什么
Well, I was in kind of a fucked state,
当时我的状况很糟
mentally, when I started there.
我指的是精神上，当我刚开始在那工作时
Um, yeah, just,I like working there.
嗯，不过我喜欢在那里工作
Tell me about your fucked state.
讲讲你当时那糟糕的状况吧
Do you want another one of these?
你要再来一杯么？
All right?
你好啊
Hey, how are you? How's it going?
嘿，你好么，最近怎么样
How did you hear about this job?
你是从哪里得知这份工作的有关情况的
A friend of mine,Denise, works here.
我一个朋友，蒂尼斯，在这里工作
Okay.
好的
So what makes you want to work with the homeless?
那你又是因为什么想要帮助无家可归者
I don't know. Uh...
不知道，呃...
I mean, we are put on this Earth to help other people, right?
我想说，我们存在世间的意义就是帮助他人，不是么？
Someone I knew told me that.
一个熟人告诉我的
Who?
谁？
Who? No one. Uh...
谁？没有，呃...
Look, I guess I just see homeless people everywhere.
我想我只是看到无家可归者无处不在
It seems like there is more and more.
他们的数量似乎还在增加
Seems like it.
似乎是这样
I guess I just want a job that, you know, means something.
我想我只是需要一份有意义的工作
Something where I don't despise myself when I come home from work.
一份让我不会在下班回家后对自己产生嫌恶感的工作
So you despise yourself?
你看轻自己？
I don't know. Uh,sure. Doesn't everyone?
可能吧，呃，当然，每个人不都是这样么？
I don't despise myself.
我可不会看轻自己
I used to be a guest here.
我曾经也是这里的常客
Then I worked here.I had a permanent bed.
后来我在这里工作，有了一个永久床位
And then I moved out.
接着我就搬出去了
I got a job in construction,became the foreman.
我在建筑工地找了份工作，成了一个工头
Then one day I came back here to give something back.
后来的某天，我回到这里，准备回报它些什么
So I've come a long way up,
我花了很长的时间向上走
but it's a quick fall down.
但回到底层却只是一瞬间的事
So I really can't afford to hate myself.
所以我真的恨不起自己
You know what I'm talking about?
你知道我在说什么吗？
You don't know what I'm talking about.
你不知道我在说什么
But that's okay.
不过没关系
Tell you what. I can put you on the fill-in list.
我可以把你放到候补名单上
If we need somebody to fill in, we'll call.
如果我们需要人手就打你电话
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, so why do they call you Captain?
嘿，他们为什么管你叫队长
Because I'm the Captain.
因为我是队长
Okay.
好吧
Just bring it by right now.
现在马上？
Okay, later.
好的，你等一下
Hey, they called from Harbor Street Inn.
嘿，港湾街旅店打电话来了
They want you to fill in tonight.
他们希望你今晚去顶班
Tonight?
今晚？
There were different types of people who worked there.
在这里工作的人形形色色
There were the religious types.
有宗教狂热者
I want to live my life the way Christ does.
我想像基督那样生活
Also, I hate my rich parents.
另外，我讨厌我有钱的父母
Hey, guys, can you bring those over here?
嘿，伙计们，能把那些东西搬过来么
There were the punks.
有小混混
Check in, sir, and we are gonna get you to the clinic.
这里登记，先生，我们带你去诊所
This place is hardcore.
这里是一个极端的所在
Plus, the pay is not bad. Next.
另外，薪水不低。下一个
There were the ex-cons.
有金盆洗手的江湖骗子
All right, next. So this dude was gonna shoot me, right?
好了，下一个。我问他说，这人是想朝我开枪么？
So, I turned sideways,'cause that is what you do.
我侧过身去，这是你第一时间要做的
You turn sideways,you take it in the arm.
转过身去，你就能用胳膊挡住子弹
I flex my bicep,I take the bullet.
我让手臂的肌肉收缩，接下了那颗子弹
And then I grabbed the gun from this guy, and I'm like bam-bam-bam-bam.
接着我从那人手里夺过枪，接着就是砰砰砰砰
Right in his fucking head, then it's like click-click-click.
直接打在他的脑袋上，几枪之后就只剩扳机扣动的咔哒声
Let me tell you, I had to disappear for a while after that.
告诉你，在那件事之后我不得不消失一段时间
All right, put your arms up.
好啦，把手举起来
Joy was an ex-cokehead and a prostitute.
乔伊曾是个可卡因成瘾的援交女
There you go, honey.
给你，亲爱的
Now, she's like a mother to the guys.
现在她看上去就像那些人的母亲
Unfortunately, in a couple of years,
不幸的是在接下来的几年里
she will be sitting in a room with a shotgun across her lap,
她需要坐在一个房间里，膝盖上摆着一把猎枪
back to dealing and smoking crack 24/7.
和毒瘾做全天候的斗争
It's hard to stay changed.
要保持现在这样真的很难
I start out working inside the cage handing out bed tickets,
我开始在笼子里发床票
（注：以铁丝网分割的小工作间通常称之为cage）
collecting people's valuables and locking them up overnight.
把住客的贵重物品收集起来，锁在一个地方过夜
It's Friday, payday. A lot of the guests have jobs.
今天是周五，发薪日。许多住客都有自己的工作
There is more money to slip into the envelopes.
有更多的钱被装进信封里
Let's go. - Hey!
快点 - 嘿！
The air is thick, stale, smells like sweat.
不再新鲜的室内空气粘稠而腐旧，充满了汗酸的气味
Back off.
退后
Friday, the drunks are more boisterous.
周五，这里会迎来更多骚嚷的醉汉
Move up, old man! Why you always got to be touching me?
往前走，老头！你为什么总要动我？
Because you are standing still, that's why.
因为你站着不动，就是这样
Every single day, I get in line, and you're right up my ass.
每天我排队的时候你都跟在我屁股后面
Maybe I should help.
也许我该上去帮忙
Yeah, maybe not.Not yet.
嗯，也许不用。暂时不用
There is a balance between escalating and defusing.
在事态的升级与减弱中存在某种平衡
Knowing when to step in, and when to back off.
你需要明白什么时候该上前，什么时候该后退
Hey, buddy,calm down!
嘿，伙计，冷静！
Oh, shit.
哦，草
I don't know that balance yet.
我还没有完全理解这种平衡
Well? Are you able to locate your feelings now?
好啦，你现在能确定自己的感觉了吧？
Yeah, this fucking hurts.
是啊，疼死我了
You are going to have a good shiner.
这个黑眼圈形状不错啊
You didn't tell me this place was such a rush.
你之前没跟我说过这里这么乱啊
It's addictive. Watch out,or you will never leave.
你会上瘾的。当心点，否则你一辈子都离不开这里了
So, how many of these people get back on their feet?
这些人里有多少最终会回到社会上打拼呢
I couldn't tell you.
不好说
But what I do know is a year from now,
但我知道的是，在过去的一年里
100-150 of the guys who come through here would be dead.
大约有100-150个来到这里的人最终都会死去
We catch them on the way down. Next stop, the morgue.
我们接住那些正在倒下的人，下一站，就是太平间
Hey. Steady Ray, as ever.
嘿，我又来了
Jonathan, how are you?
乔纳桑，你最近怎么样
So, I thought I might stay over tonight.
我想我得在这过夜
I find myself momentarily between places.
我刚发现自己转悠到你这附近来了
The thing is, Claire's mom is here. She's staying with us.
问题是，克莱尔的妈妈来了，她和我们住在一起
That is okay.I'll sleep on the couch.
没关系。我可以睡沙发上
No, that is where she's staying.
不行，她就睡在那里
We are renovating the guest room.
我们的客房正在整修
Tell her to get the fuck off and let me sleep with her.
告诉她赶紧腾个地让我和她一起睡
Is she nice?
她人不错吧？
Yeah. You met her?
是啊，你见过她？
Mother-in-law, mother-in-law
丈母娘，丈母娘
Mother-in-law
丈母娘
Hey, honey!
嘿，亲爱的！
Shh.
嘘
I mean, this wasn't because of the old
客房翻修不是因为什么老掉牙的
burning-of-the-Christmas-tree thing, was it?
“点燃圣诞树”之类的事造成的吧？
（注：圣诞节之后的一日，即主显节时，基督教有点燃圣诞树的传统习俗）
No. That's ancient history.
不是，那只是个古代传说
Exactly, because it was really funny. You got to admit, it was.
确实是，不过它很有意思，你得承认这点
Yeah. That was a lot of fun.
是啊，很有意思
Sure, all right. Well, okay,give Claire de Lune my love.
当然，帮我跟克莱尔打声招呼
And I'm going to try Dugan.
我去杜根家看看
He is always begging me to come over
他总求我过去他家
and provide some free entertainment for
给他和他那倒霉老婆
him and his miserable missus.
讲点好玩的事
Dugan moved to Florida.
杜根搬去佛罗里达了
He did? Moved to Florida? Why the hell would he do that?
他真搬了？到佛罗里达？为了什么？
I don't know,the weather.
不清楚，天气的缘故吧
Oh, the weather.
哦，天气
Okay, looks like I'm going to head to my suite at the Ritz.
看来我得去我利兹酒店的套房睡了
（注：利兹-卡尔顿酒店，纽约的顶级酒店之一）
I'm sorry. - Okay,Ray.
真的很不好意思 - 没关系，雷
Good night.All right. Good night.
晚安。好的，晚安
Take care. Give the lovely missus my love.
小心点。记得帮我向可爱的夫人问好
Don't forget to write.
别忘了写作
Yeah, I'll write.In jail.
啊，我会写的。在班房里
Ray?
雷？
I'm coming.
我来了
For the next few weeks I lived out of my cab.
接下来的几个星期，我都睡在出租车里
Renting it 24 hours a day,seven days a week.
我开始不间断地运营，一天24小时，一周7天
It's a wonderful life.
真是美妙的生活啊
You shit at the bus station,
你在公车站拉屎
you shower at the Y.
在基督教青年会冲澡
（注：Y=YMCA=Young Men's Christian Association）
But it's not all fun and games.
但生活也并非都是游戏和娱乐
Cabbies get shot in the head every night.
每天晚上都有出租车司机被枪打穿脑袋
Bamo! Right in the jugular.Right in the fucking jugular.
砰！正打在颈动脉上，就他妈直接打在颈动脉上
I'll ram it down their throat and rip their insides right out.
我会用这个砍断他们的喉咙，把他们的内脏翻出来
Hurry up!
快点！
The police said I hit someone,or some fucking thing.
警察说我撞到了某个人，或者是别的什么操蛋东西上
What can I say to that?
我能说什么呢？
Now, I have no license,no cab, no place to sleep.
现在我没了执照，没了车，没了睡觉的地方
Perhaps I'll start a new book,Memoirs of a Moron!
也许我该写本新书，叫《一个蠢蛋的回忆录》
Memoirs of a fucking moron.
《一个傻×蠢蛋的回忆录》
After the cage,I work housing.
从笼子里出来之后，我开始做杂务
It's more intense. You are not protected behind steel mesh.
挑战更加严峻，现在你已经离开了铁丝网的保护
Okay, grab a cup,have a good shower.
好了，拿一个杯子，好好冲个澡
Hey, I'll meet you in the hot room in 10 minutes.
嘿，10分钟后我在桑拿室等你
Okay. If I'm not there,
好的，如果我没去的话
just take your clothes off and start without me.
你就脱掉衣服自己来
Okay.
行
The hot room smells of superheated sweat, quick fermented.
桑拿房里充斥的汗水味会在高温下迅速发酵
Excuse me.
不好意思
I need a new pair of pants.
我需要一条新裤子
No problem. I'll be right back.
没问题 我马上回来
Hey, how do I know what size he wears?
我怎么知道他穿几号？
You ask him.
你问他啊
At Harbor Street you write up every day's events in the log,
在港湾街，你要把每天的事件都写进日志里
and you read off your entry that night.
等到晚上你需要把自己的记录通读一遍
He's not gonna bite.
他不会咬人的
I take that opportunity to practice.
我利用这个机会练习写作
"9:10, Isaac Clegg fell out of bed, and the bed fell on him.
“9点10分，埃萨克・克雷格从床上掉了下来，翻倒的床又压在了他身上。”
"The skin of a drunk splits open easily,
“醉汉的皮肤能被轻易地刮裂
"their blood flows more freely,thinned out by the booze.
“他们经由酒精稀释的血液流动起来更为自由
"The nurse is gone for the evening
“晚上，护士下了班
"and Isaac is loath to go to the hospital.
“而埃萨克不愿去医院
"I make an attempt to bandage him. "
“我便尝试着为他包扎
I'm just gonna wrap this around you. You okay?
我现在用这个帮你把伤口包上，你没事吧？
"9:30, I was able to convince George D.
“9点30分，我终于说服了乔治D
"to sit still for his monthly de-Iousing."
“安静地坐下来接受每月一次的灭虱工作。”
My beloved family, they beheaded me, their beloved Queen.
我可爱的家人，他们把我的头砍了下来，那是众人爱戴的女王
I loved them. They were my friends.
我爱他们，他们是我的朋友
"Lice thrive so well on George's body
“乔治身上的虱子长势茂盛
"that they can be seen crawling over him at 20 paces."
“我能看见它们以20步的速度在他的身上爬行
I would never hurt them.
我不会伤害他们的
I would never kill them.
我永远不会杀死他们
Hey, it's okay, man.I understand, George.
好了，没关系的，我能理解，乔治
But, I mean, they beheaded you, didn't they? So why not?
可是，他们都把你的头砍下来了不是么，为什么不杀了他们？
This is the right decision, George.
这是正确的选择，乔治
"Nothing in the shelter makes me understand my purpose more
“没有比杀死一个流浪汉身上的虫子，
"than to kill bugs off of a homeless man's flesh..."
“或是为他穿上捐赠的，被他人丢弃的衣服，
Okay. All right.
好吧
Let's get you cleaned up.
让我帮你清理下身体
"...to dress him well in donated, cast-off clothes,
“看见他第二天在加热炉旁大笑，
"and to see him the next day laughing beside a burning barrel."
“更能使我理解自己工作的目的的事了。”
Okay, Nick.Very expressive.
好吧，尼克，非常有表现力的文字
I like the stuff about Isaac being loath to go to the hospital.
我喜欢埃萨克不愿去医院的那段
Thank you.
谢谢
How about we let the next person read their entry?
让下一个人读吧
"10:00 p.m., fight broke out in reading area.
“晚上10点，阅读区发生了一场打斗
"10:30, Wally G. Caught smoking in bed."
“10点半，沃利 G.在床上吸烟， 被抓住了。”
Which I confiscated,by the way.
顺便说一下，我没收了他的作案工具
Lucky number 41.
幸运号码是，41
Hey, what are you up to after work?
嘿，下班后你想干什么
Nothing.
不干什么
Thank you.
谢谢
I thought we were just friends.
我觉得我们只是普通朋友
Shut up.
把嘴闭上
What's all this?
这些都是什么
Just old letters.
以前的信
Is this from your father?
你爸写的？
He was in jail?
他以前蹲过监狱？
He passed forged checks
他用了伪造的支票
in between writing the great American novel.
在写那部伟大的美国小说的空档里用的
Nice.
不错
Are these all from your dad?
这些都是你爸寄来的？
Yeah.
嗯
There's like a hundred letters in here.
看起来有一百封呢
This is yours?
这是你的？
Don't read that.
别看那个
"Loaded, I say.
“喝醉了，我说
"Wasted, looped, lit, off my ass, befuddled, reeling, tanked,
“烂醉如泥，酩酊昏暗，东西不分，天旋地转，
"punch-drunk, mean drunk,maintenance drunk,
“也许愤怒不已，恶语连篇，无比节制
"sloppy drunk, happy drunk, weepy drunk, blind drunk, dead drunk,
“抑或多愁善感，捧腹大笑，以泪洗面，黑暗一片，人事不省，
"serious drinker,hard drinker."
“酒徒，严肃者，猛者。”
What is this?
这是什么？
Nothing. Some poetry. It's shit.
没什么，一些诗，写得很烂。
"Polluted, blitzed,shattered, zonked,
“腐蚀，沉醉，破碎，恍惚
"ossified, annihilated,fossilized,
“僵直，崩倒，石化，
"stinko, blotto, legless,smashed, soaked,
“痛饮，烂醉，双脚悬离地面，重重落下，浸入酒池之中
"screwed, blasted,
“烂醉，而后枯萎
"hammered, tore up, ripped up,ripped, destroyed."
“沉没，而后分裂；分裂，而后毁灭。”
Cheerful stuff.
挺好玩的
No one will ever read it.
没人会去读的
I just did.
我刚才就读了
Come back to bed.
回床上来
What will you give me if I do?
那你是不是该来点刺激的？
Dear Mr. President.
亲爱的总统先生
The proper study of mankind is man.
男人是研究人类的最好对象
Ortega y Gasset defined genius as the ability to invent one's occupation.
奥特加・伊・加塞特将天才定义为有能力为自身创造职业者
（注：奥特加・伊・加塞特，20世纪的西班牙思想家）
I am a writer,a poet, a storyteller.
我是一个作家，一个诗人，一个叙事者
The library will be closing in 10 minutes.
图书馆将在10分钟后闭馆
If the present holds any promise of the years ahead,
如果现在要对未来下一个定论的话，有一件事是肯定的
the United States can look forward to many generations of
美国政府以后就得指望一帮
executives unable to spell their names correctly.
连自己名字都拼不对的官员后代了
Yours, as ever,Jonathan R. Flynn.
您一如既往忠实的，乔纳桑・R・弗林
Give me that. That's my personal property, you ape.
把它给我，这是我的私人财产，你这头猩猩
Thank you.
谢谢
Tonight, I'm doing a little after-hours banking.
今晚，我要做一次投资
I'm depositing a check for $750,000,
我要存一张价值75万美元的支票
an advance for my novel The Button Man.
就当做是我那本小说《纽扣人》的预支
It's classic.
它绝对是一流的
They're making a movie,a movie of my life.
他们在拍一部电影，有关我生平的电影
Excuse me?
能再说一次么？
They're making a movie.
他们在拍一部电影
Someone, behind the wall.
墙后面的某个人
They are?
是么？
Who in living hell would want to make a movie about your life?
到底有谁愿意拍一部有关你生平的电影呢？
That would be one boring,redundant, piece of shit movie.
一定是部无趣，冗长，垃圾的电影
Here you go.
给你
You have to take it outside, dear.
去外面喝，亲爱的
Oh, what a pleasant surprise. Thank you.
哦，真是个惊喜，谢谢
You're welcome.
不客气
Dawn of a new day.
新一天的曙光
I like that.
我喜欢这话
I'm going to write a poem about you, Dawn.
我要为你写首诗，小曙光
You are too sweet.
你可真贴心
Cheers.Cheers.
干杯 - 干杯
Dawn. Sawn...
黎明，锯...
He's seen this before. Bums sprawled out from drinking.
他以前看过这样的场景：流浪者醉后四仰八叉地躺在地上
But he has never actually stood over the blowers,
但这是他第一次确实地站在中央暖气的风箱上
let the hot air seep into his clothes.
让升起的热气注满衣服的每个缝隙
The air is sucked out of the library.
这些热气从图书馆里被抽出
Even on the coldest nights there is too much heat inside.
即使是每年最冷的几个夜晚，那里的热量也能多到溢出
It's another prison,these blowers.
这些风箱好比成排异色的牢房
Because once you have landed,you can't leave.
一旦落脚，便无法离去
Because one step off the blower is cold, hypothermia cold,
只要从牢房中踏出一步，等待你的就是严寒，刺骨的严寒
now that you are sodden with steam.
现在你已然被蒸汽包围
The blower is a room of heat with no walls.
风箱就像一个充盈着热气却没有墙壁的房间
My father is an invisible man, in an invisible room,
父亲就像一个无形的人，身处一处无形的房间
in the invisible city.
隐没在这座无形的城市里
Whoo!
呼！
I really appreciate the help, sir.
很感谢你的帮助，先生
Call me Carlos. - Okay. Carlos.
叫我卡洛斯就好了 - 好吧，卡洛斯
So, Jerry, how many nights have you been homeless?
那么，杰瑞，你已经无家可归几个晚上了？
Just one night. One bad night with the wife, boy.
就一晚，我是和老婆大人吵架了，小子
That is all it takes,one bad night.
就一个晚上，糟糕的晚上
You got that right.
正解
What is up, Nick?
什么事啊？
For the new guys,no bottles or weapons, okay?
告诉新来的，别喝酒也别带武器
All right, you're good.
好的
Stretch your arms out for me, sir. Please? Thank you.
先生，能请你把手臂张开么？谢谢
All right.Step up.
好了，过来
I'd like a room for the evening.
我想要房间过夜
You want a bed?
一张床？
That'll do for now.
可以
Well, this is a pleasant surprise.
哦，这还真是个惊喜
So, you're employed here now?
你现在在这里上班？
Yes, I'm employed here.
嗯，我在这里上班
Well, I approve. We are put on this Earth to help other people.
我赞同你的做法，我们存在世间的意义就是帮助他人
You must be gathering some excellent material.
你是在收集素材呢吧
Hey. You giving out tickets, or what?
嘿，你是在发床票还是干嘛呢？
Many thanks.
十分感谢
And if a private room does open up, I'd be grateful.
如果能有个单人间的话就更好了
Hey, what's up?
嘿，怎么回事
My father is here.
我爸来了
What? - My father, he's here.
什么？ - 我爸，他来了
He's staying here,he is a guest tonight.
他今晚是这儿的住客
Jesus.
天哪
Oh, shit.
哦，该死的
Your dad is sleeping here.Your own father.
你爸在这儿过夜
Nick, man, you are the unluckiest guy I know.
尼克，你是我认识的最走霉运的人了
Thanks, Carlos. Just keep it to yourself, man. Please?
谢谢，卡洛斯，别告诉别人成不？
No worries.
没问题
Hey, Nick. You feel like going home tonight?
嘿，尼克，你今晚打算回家么
No. Why?
不，怎么了？
Because your father is here.
因为你爸来了啊
So you heard about that.
你也听说了啊
Yeah.
是啊
Who else knows?
还有谁知道了？
We are with you, man.
我们都知道了
Fucking Carlos.
卡洛斯这操蛋的
Maybe you could take the night off. You know, I can get a fill-in.
你今晚可以请假啊，我能顶你的班
No.
不用
It's my job.I work here.
这是我的工作
Let's go.
走吧
Come with me.
跟我来
Bottom bunk.
底铺
Nicholas.
尼古拉斯
Interesting view.
这儿的景色真有意思
I thought you were staying at a friend's place?
我以为你都睡在朋友家
A couple of things fell through.
呃，这中间发生了很多事
I was bunking in my cab for a while,
我在我的出租车里睡了几个晚上
but that is no longer possible.
但是现在不行了
So I have been sleeping alfresco.
所以我直接打地铺了
Alfresco? You mean outside? For how long?
打地铺？你睡在大街上？多久了？
Three weeks or so.
三个礼拜左右
Don't look so grave. This is a great opportunity for me.
表情别那么沉重嘛，这对我来说可是个好机会
What opportunity?
什么好机会
The opportunity to freeze to death?
被冻死的好机会？
The opportunity to see how the other half lives.
看看纽约的另一半人民是怎么过活的好机会
The poor, the downtrodden.
穷人，被压迫者
I'm doing the same thing here as you are, gathering material.
我在做和你一样的事，收集素材
No, I'm not gathering material. This is my life.
我不是在收集素材，这就是我的生活
Life is gathering material.
生活就是收集素材
I like that. Help me remember that.
哦，这个句子不错，帮我记着
They won't even let me bring a goddamned pen up here.
他们连支该死的笔都不让我带进来
Can't you do anything about that?
你不能帮我做点什么么？
No. Don't you have any clout around here?
不能 - 你在这不能施加半点影响么？
Sorry.
不好意思
Well, anyway, my writing is going extremely well, by the by.
顺便说一下，我的写作进展非常完美
I'm already almost done with my revisions to Chapter 37.
我差不多已经修改完第37章了
Perhaps I'll let you read it someday. It's classic.
也许哪天我会给你看看，真是一流的小说
Okay, look, you can't stay here. Why not?
好啦，你不能永远呆在这 - 为什么？
Because I work here.
因为我在这工作
Well, don't worry. This is only a very temporary situation.
别担心啊，这情况只是暂时的
I don't want to disrupt your life in the least.
我没有半点打扰你生活的意思
I have a friend of mine who's
begging me to move down to Florida.
我一个朋友都求我搬去佛罗里达了
He has a guest house and a job there for me.
他在那为我准备了一间客房和差事
Okay. Florida,that sounds great.
好吧，佛罗里达，听起来不错啊
In the meantime,
与此同时
this is an excellent opportunity for
这也是一个绝佳的
you and I to make up for lost time.
让你我弥补失去的父子时间的机会
Destiny has brought us together for one fleeting moment.
命运赏赐给我们一段短暂共处的时光
Let us not spit in its eye.
请别坏了它的好意
Thank you again, man.
谢谢惠顾啊老兄
And you know, let me know if that shit don't work out.
如果不够劲的话再来找我
Let me know, all right?
记得啊
Okay.We'll see you.
好，再见
All right.
嗯
I mean, you could ask him to stay here for a few days.
你可以叫他来这住几天啊
No, he can't.
不行
I don't even know if the Florida thing is real.
我甚至不知道佛罗里达那码事是不是真的
I hope so,for your sake.
从为你着想的角度来说，希望是吧
Just weed, right?
只卖大麻？
Excuse me?
什么？
You're only selling weed, right?
你只做大麻生意吧
Yeah, just weed.
是啊，只有大麻
I'm just saying,he's your father.
我只是说说，他说到底还是你爸啊
Uh...
呃
I've had father figures.
我脑子里有好几个老爸的形象
All right, Nick! Keep your eye on the ball.
好啦，尼克，眼睛看球
They were all burned up.
他们都死翘翘了
It's amazing what can happen to the human body, Nick.
有时候能发生在人身上的事都神奇得很啊，尼克
Hey! What the hell are you showing him?
喂，你在给他看什么东西？
Hey, sweetie.What the fuck, Travis?
嘿，甜心 - 特拉维斯，这他妈的是什么？
Pick that up! Come on,I want to talk to you.
收起来！快点，我得和你谈谈
I thought he was a little young to be driving a car.
我想他要开车年纪还小了点
You could have killed yourself. Get inside!
你会弄死你自己的，进屋去！
Thank you very much.
真的非常感谢
You're welcome.
不客气
Have a good day.You, too.
祝您愉快 - 你也是
My mom had a lot of different boyfriends, growing up.
我妈有过非常多男友，越来越多
Come on, buddy.Good job.
快点，伙计 - 漂亮
But I never had a father.
但我从没有过一个真正的父亲
Luckily, I had a mother.
幸运的是，我还有她
Hey, who you playing ball with?
嘿，你在和谁玩呢
Nobody. Myself.
没人，就我一个
Get your mitt.
陪我玩嘛
Honey, I'm exhausted.
亲爱的，我快累死了
Okay.
好吧
All right.
算啦
Let me get my mitt.Heads up!
我拿手套去，抬头！
Good one. Thanks.
漂亮 - 谢谢
I'll be right back. - Okay.
马上回来 - 好
You are not listening to me. I'm listening.
你没在听我说话 - 我在听
He stole $30 from me!
他偷了我30美元！
I understand that.Hey, Nick!
我知道 - 嘿，尼克
Jonathan asked me to give this letter to you, man.
乔纳桑叫我把这封信给你
So he's some kind of famous writer?
所以他算是个名作家？
Yeah, that's why he's staying at Harbor Street.
是啊，所以他才跑到港湾街来的
Dear Nick, many deep thanks for your warm welcome.
亲爱的尼克，我由衷感谢你的热情接待
I must say you seemed anxious.
你看上去有些焦虑
Of course, writers,especially poets,
当然了对于一个作家，特别是诗人来说
are particularly prone to madness.
疯狂是一种极易出现的倾向
Hey, babe.
嘿，宝贝
Okay.
好啦
There exists a striking association
在创造的灵感与躁郁的消沉之间
between creativity and manic depression.
存在某种惊人的联系
The only important thing,though, is to simply do the work.
尽管如此，最重要的还是着手去做
It's not a sharp pain, it's a dull pain. I haven't eaten in two days.
不是阵阵的刺痛，是持续的钝痛，我已经两天没吃饭了
Hey, straight through the back, down the stairs.
穿过后面，下楼
Most of these guys here are
这里的大部分都是
a bunch of fucking deadbeat panhandlers and pederasts.
一群游手好闲的乞丐和鸡奸犯
These perverts, they wouldn't last a second in federal prison.
那些好色之徒，他们要是进了联邦监狱，一定熬不过半天
They are all homosexuals. I despise homosexuals, and they despise me.
他们都是同性恋，我看到同性恋就恶心，他们看到我也会恶心
I know what I'm talking about.I talk the straight talk.
我知道我在说什么，我讲话很直接
I was locked up in federal prison with choirboys,
我曾经和唱诗班的小孩一起被关在联邦监狱里
that's for sure. Next, please.
千真万确 - 下一个
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey.
嘿
Hi.
嗨
See this? Uh-huh.
看见没？ - 嗯哼
Don't ever become a writer.
绝对不要当什么作家
Just around the corner to the right, follow the hallway.
前面转角向右，沿着过道走下去
You know where to go.
你就能看到了
Jesus. Hey, what happened to you?
老天啊，你这是怎么了
I'm fine.
我没事
You're fine? You should get to the clinic.
你没事？你得去医务室
You should see the other cocksuckers. This is nothing.
你去管其他白痴吧，我没事
By the way, I have a little gift for you.
顺便，有个礼物给你
From one writer to another.
我以作家的身份把它传给你
Is there a tailor here?
这儿有裁缝么
No.
没有
I'm going to need a new coat.
我想我需要一件新的外套
Okay.
好
All right, so I won't be there.
好吧，那我就不去了
But I'll get there next time, okay?
下次吧，可以么？
All right.
好
Hey.
嘿
You are not just selling weed, right?
你不只是做大麻生意吧？
Watch your hands.Watch your hands.
小心手，小心手
Why should a truly great writer
为什么一个真正伟大的作家
be subjected to these fucking indignities?
要接受这种无礼的对待
There we go.
这玩意
What are you doing? That's my property.
你干什么？这是我的东西
Come on,get out of here.
快点，从这出去
That's my property.That's my property.
这是我的，我的
Fucking homo.
操你妈的死基佬
Calm down.Calm down, now.
冷静点，冷静点
I'm going to transform this cesspool of a world.
我要改变这个污秽的世界
I'm going to transform it with a fucking word!
我只要用一个词就能改变这个世界！
You know, he is not going anywhere.
他哪都没去
It's been weeks.
已经好几个礼拜了
What do you suggest I do about it?
你觉得我该怎么办
Get a job somewhere else?
换个地方工作？
Hey,
嘿
you want to do some blow?
你想吸点粉么？
Um...
嗯..
I despise blow.
我不喜欢
Turns people into fucking scumbags.
吸粉的人最后都成了人渣
But you go ahead if you want to.
如果你想吸就吸吧
12:30, Floyd Perkins reports physical altercation.
12点30分，弗洛伊德・铂金斯报告有口角发生
Report completed.
完毕
2:00 a.m., shift change. Brian gets permission to sign out.
凌晨2点，换班时间，布莱恩离岗
7:00 p.m., Jon Flynn was caught
晚上7点，乔纳桑・弗林
trying to smuggle a bottle in tonight.
企图偷带烈酒进入，被发现
At first he was abusive, but he calmed down and was given a warning.
起初他情绪激动，后来被警告后情绪有所平复
He wasn't put out for the night?
他没进来？
It's cold out there, man.
外面可是很冷啊
He asked me to give a letter to you.
他叫我给你这封信
Nick,
尼克，
I thought last evening at Harbor Street,
我在港湾街沉思了一晚
waiting for 8:00 p.m. to come...
等待早晨8时的到来
I thought if your very beautiful mother were alive,
如果你那美丽的母亲还活着
and if she could somehow see this scene,
如果她能看到这幅场景
her son at work and his father a resident
他的儿子在港湾街收容所工作
at Harbor Street shelter for the homeless.
而他的父亲是那里的住客
The beaten, the sad, the losers in life's great game.
和那些醉汉，乞丐，以及被生活这场巨大的游戏所打败的人比肩而坐
Jody would have laughed loudly at the entire macabre scene.
这幅可怕的场景想必会使朱迪忍俊不禁
She was the most beautiful woman in the world.
她真是世界上最美的女人
She was the love of my life.
他是我命中挚爱
The light of my love.
爱情之光
If she were here today, she would be with me now.
如果她现在还活着，她会陪着我的
What happened
这是...
to my face?
我的脸怎么了
I'm only 28 years old.
我才刚刚28岁啊
Why do I look like this?
为什么我变成了这样
Excuse me? What happened to me?
不好意思 - 我这是怎么了？
What happened! What have you done to me?
怎么回事！你们对我做了什么？
What have you done to me?
你们对我做了什么？
He kept shouting at me that he was 28 years old,
他一直朝我大叫，说他只有28岁
and it just... It kind of freaked me out, and I just...
真的是...我有点被吓到了...我...
What are you looking at?
你在看什么
Nothing.
没什么
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Don't be sorry. Sorry for what?
别这么说，不好意思什么
That it freaked you out?
就因为那吓到你了？
It's nothing.
没什么
Wait until you have been here a few months.
等你在这里呆几个月你就知道了
Easy, Nick.Take it easy.
放松点，尼克，放轻松
I am taking it easy.
我很放松
This isn't me we are talking about.
又不是在说我
No, it's not.
当然不是
Go ahead.
继续吧
11:15, tables and chairs put away in the gym from overflow.
11点15分，桌椅被收进健身房
Did you read my last letter?
你看了我之前那封信么
Yes.
嗯
Beautifully written,wasn't it?
写得很美吧？
Don't write to me about my fucking mother.
别写信跟我说我那该死的老妈的事
Your fucking mother?
你那该死的老妈？
Your fucking mother? How dare you refer to her that way.
该死的老妈？你怎么敢这样称呼她？
How dare you say,"How dare you," to me.
你又有什么资格对我说“你怎么敢”这种话
Well, let me rephrase it. Don't fucking write to me about my mother.
好吧，我换个说法，别他妈写信跟我说我妈的事
It only makes you sound childish using profanity like that.
你说出这样不敬的话只会使你显得不成熟
Sorry, you don't get to patronize me. Okay?
别在我面前摆出一副屈尊俯就的样子成么？
You don't get to pretend to be my father
你不需要假装是我的父亲
and you don't get to write about my mother.
你也没必要写信说我妈的事
In fact, stop writing me at all.
事实上，我想说的是，你别给我写信了
Stop writing me letters.
别给我写了
You should save them.
你应该把那些信收好
They'll be won'th money someday.
总有一天它们会变得值钱
I have saved them,actually.
我收了
I have over 100.That's enough.
我已经有超过100封了，够了
You saved them. Good.
你有把它们收好啊，不错
You bring liquor in here again,you are barred. End of story.
如果你再带酒进来，你就永远别想在这睡觉了，你就玩完了
Eano the Beano tells me you are into drugs.
有人告诉我你吸毒了
Who the fuck is Eano the Beano? How would he know that?
谁啊？他怎么知道的？
Everybody knows,the word is out.
大家都知道了，消息已经传开了
You know, if so,good luck to you.
如果是真的，祝你好运
But don't waste your talent.
别浪费了你的才能
I don't have any talent.
我没有什么才能
I find that hard to believe.
这可真是难以置信
Why? Because you're so incredibly talented?
为什么？因为你是如此难以置信地有才？
Yes.
当然
Okay, so where is it?
好吧，那你的“才”呢
The masterpiece.
那本杰作
Where are you hiding it?
你把它藏哪了？
Can I read it? Does it even exist?
我能读读它么？它真的存在么？
Do you exist,Nicholas Flynn?
你是存在的么，尼可拉斯・弗林？
Do you even know?
你自己清楚么？
I, Jonathan Flynn, exist! I know that much.
我，乔纳桑・弗林，是确实存在的！我清楚地知道
Jonathan Flynn exists!
乔纳桑・弗林！是一个实在！
Shut the fuck up!
她妈的闭嘴！
You shut the fuck up,
你他妈的才给我闭嘴
or my son will evict you!
不然我儿子就把你撵出去！
I want you to leave here.
你能不能别住这里了
Find some fucking place,
快她妈去找一个
some old drinking buddy who is suicidal enough to take you in.
想要自虐的人收容你吧
I'm a sought-after house guest.
可是有一堆人求我去他们家呢
Yeah, because you're an excellent raconteur. Right?
当然啦，因为你是个极好的说书人，对不对？
Yes! Good night!
当然！ 晚安！
Remember something, Nicholas.
记住，尼古拉斯
You are me!
你就是我！
You are me! I made you!
你就是我！我生了你！
You are me!
你就是我！
I am not you! I am not you!
我不是你！ 不是！
Yes, you are! Go to Florida!
你就是！ - 滚去佛罗里达吧！
You are me!
你！就！是！我！
Shut the fuck up! Everybody, shut the fuck up!
他妈的安静地，每个人都给我安静点
Night.
晚安
I asked to fill in on the outreach van.
我换到了运输部工作
I can't stand to be in the shelter
我已经无法忍受收容所里的混乱
where my drunken jack-in-the-box can appear at any moment.
在那里，我家那位小丑随时都可能出现在我面前
Hey, you are the guy whose father is a guest here, aren't you?
嘿，你就是那个老爹在我们收容所里的老兄吧
No. That guy is just a drunk.
不是，那人只是个醉鬼而已
A con man, he has nothing to do with me.
一个江湖骗子，和我没有半点关系
Yeah. No, of course not.
当然啦，当然
Okay, we're ready.
好了，我们这准备完成
Yeah. Okay.
好
The hours are 9:00 at night until 5:00 in the morning.
工作时间是晚上9点到清晨5点
Hi, I got a sandwich for you.
嗨，这个三明治给你
Hey, excuse me,sir, sorry to wake you.
不好意思吵醒您了
I got a sandwich here.
这里有三明治
You want to get inside?
想要进来么？
"Jonathan Flynn responded to a guest's request that he share a can of deodorant
“乔纳桑・弗林对一个要从他手上拿除臭剂的人
"with an intense verbal assault towards
发起了强烈的言语攻击
"the other guest on racial and sexual themes.
“内容涉及种族主义和生殖器等等
"Mr. Flynn would not respond to intervention.
“他无视工作人员的调停
"In fact, he accelerated his verbal assault. "
“事实上，他的言语暴力因此而升级了
Are you okay?
你还好吧
Yeah.
嗯
Jonathan's a little out of control tonight.
乔纳桑今晚有点失控了
"The SPO, Chris, Gabriel, and Brian,
“由于他拒绝穿上衣服，
"escorted Mr. Flynn to the brown lobby wrapped in a sheet,
“SPO小组：克里斯，加布瑞尔和布莱恩，
"as he had refused to dress himself. "
“在他身上裹了被单，把他送到了大厅里。”
...my vision, The Confessions of Christopher Cobb.
...在我看来，《克里斯托弗・柯布的自白书》
My father rants... "In the beginning was the Word."
父亲咆哮着...“最开始便是这样赫然的文字”
Salinger, Twain...
塞林格，马克・吐温
... piss on the floor unnoticed...Jonathan Robinson Flynn.
... 他不知道自己尿在了地上 ...“乔纳桑・罗宾森・弗林”
I was brought into this world to help other people.
我存在世间的意义就是去帮助他人
Ignored.
对我的出现不予理会
I was brought into this world to write my masterpiece, and it's written!
我存在世间的意义便是完成我的杰作，现在它已经完成了！
We all need to create the story
在漫长的人生里
that will make sense of our lives.
我们都要写下一部有意义的故事
I stood behind the priest and held his robe...
我站在神父后面，手握他的法袍
Make sense of our daily tasks.
对我们的每日生活存有意义的故事
...as he put the host on each tongue.
...看着他将圣餐递上每一人的舌尖
All the little girls lined up.Their tongues out.
那些小女孩们排成一列，伸出他们的舌头
Yet each night, the doubts return, howling through him.
尽管每天夜里，那些本已驱散的疑虑会再度归来，在他的身体里悲号
Suck-o my cock-o!
含着！我的！鸡巴！
You! You! Where is your faith?
你！你！你的信仰在哪里？
Where is your faith? Without faith you are nothing!
你的信仰在哪里？无信仰者于世皆为尘埃！
You are nothing!
皆为尘埃！
Nothing!
尘埃！
You are nothing!
皆为尘埃！
Nick.
尼克
I'm heading out.
我要走了
Okay.
好吧
Why?
为什么
Because you are drunk and I have to work tomorrow.
你喝醉了，我明天还得上班
So do you.
你也是
I'm not drunk.
我没醉
You're not going to stay over?
不打算通宵了？
I'm going home.
我要回家了
I think,
我觉得
after what happened today,maybe you shouldn't be drinking.
今天发生了这种事，你怎么还有心情喝酒
What happened today?
什么事？
The vote.
投票的事
Jon has created problems in housing.
你爸已经惹出了一堆乱子
He is not getting any better.
他一点正常的迹象都没有
He is only getting worse.
一天比一天更糟
I think it's time that we vote on whether to bar him.
我觉得我们该投票表决是不是该禁止他出入收容所了
I'm sorry, I don't think we should bar Jonathan.
抱歉，我觉得我们不该对他下禁令
I agree.
同意
We will vote on it.
我们投票决定
Well, what day isn't fucked up?
有哪天不是糟糕的呢？
Right?
不是么？
Do you want to get out of here?
想出去么？
Sleep at my place?
来我那睡？
Uh, no.
呃，不
You go ahead.I will see you tomorrow.
你走吧，明天见
Okay? All right.
好吧
Who votes to let Jonathan continue to stay here?
有谁赞成乔纳桑继续呆在这里的？
It's freezing outside. We can't just put him out there.
外面会冻死人的，我们不能赶他出去
Nick.
尼克
Hey.
嘿
Yeah?
怎么了？
I think you need to get some help.
我觉得你需要人帮忙
What?
什么？
You need some help.
你需要人帮忙
Need help?
要帮忙么？
What? Need help?
什么？帮什么忙？
Nah, it wasn't your friends who trashed the place.
算了，又不是你的朋友把垃圾扔得到处都是
Have you seen my notebook?
看到我的笔记本了么？
No. - Fuck.
没有 - 该死的
I got to hand in an assignment.
我要拿来交作业的
Will you let me know if you find it?
找到了跟我说一声可以么？
If it were up your ass...
如果它就在你屁股上...
（注：同前一个，意为“不关我事）
I'd know where it was.
我就肯定知道它在哪了
Can I have a hit?
能尝一口么？
Smoke crack before? No.
之前吸过强可卡因么？没有
Don't. I haven't left the pipe for three days.
那最好别试，我已经连吸三天了
Nick, I read your short story.
尼克，我读了你的短篇
I'm sorry I read it, I don't mean to intrude on your privacy.
我不是故意要看的，没有侵犯你隐私的意思
I have to tell you, you have always been so perceptive,
但我要说一件事，你从小时候开始
since you were a child.
就有敏锐的感知力
Mom?
妈？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Do you miss him? -What?
你想他了？ 什么？
No. Of course not.
当然不是
The only person I give a damn about is sitting right here.
我在乎的唯一一个人就坐在我面前呢
So then why are you crying?
那你为什么哭了？
I'm not.
没有
I'm not crying.
我没哭
Are you going to finish that?
你不吃了么？
This?
这个？
Um...
嗯...
This ice cream?
这个冰淇淋？
Am I going to eat it?
你问我还要吃么？
No.
不吃了
Thanks.
谢谢
I went to the beach,
我去了海滩
but I was unable to throw myself in the ocean.
但我没法把自己扔进海里
I did the best I could.
我尽了最大的努力
I tried to hold it all together.
我试着把它们拼凑到一起
I love you
我爱你
and I love my dad.
我也爱他
Come on, you're good.
好了，可以了
Right up the steps.
上楼
All right, Jonathan, you can't come in here. You have been banned.
好啦，乔纳桑，你不能进来，你被禁止入内了
I've been banned? Yes, for two months.
我被禁了？ 对，两个月
Who banned me?
谁干的
It doesn't matter,you have been banned.
这不重要，总之你被禁了
I have been banned?
我被禁了？
Yes, you have been banned.
没错
Does my son know about this?
我儿子知道这事么？
Yes, he knows about it.
当然，他知道
Where is he? It doesn't matter, you have to go.
他在哪？这不重要，请你离开
Father murderer, where are you? I need you to leave.
不孝子，你在哪？ 请你离开这里
Nicholas! Where are you? Come on.
尼古拉斯！你在哪？快点
Father murderer!
不孝子！
Father murderer! Where are you?
不孝子！你丫人呢？
Come on, guys, clear out. Come out!
快点，伙计们，散开。 - 出来！
Come out and face me!
出来面对我啊！
What are you doing? What are you doing? Father murderer!
你在干什么呢？你干什么呢？不孝子！
Jonathan.Come out! Come out!
乔纳桑！ - 出来！出来！
Where are you hiding? In some little closet,
你藏在哪了，是不是躲在衣柜里
sucking your mama's tit,father murderer?
吸你妈妈的奶呢不孝子？！
I could have jerked...I could have jerked off
我当时就该把你
and flushed you down the toilet.
射进厕所里用水冲走了！
Father murderer, come out and face me!
不孝子！出来和我对质！
Outside!
出去！
Face me,you father murderer!
出来啊你这个不孝子！
Face me!
出来！
Out the door, man!
出去！
Hey.
嘿
Look, Nick.
尼克
We're done.
我们之间结束了
Excuse me? We're done.
什么？- 我们之间完了
You look really fucked up, by the way.
顺便说一下，你看起来脸色很差
I wouldn't let Captain see you like that.
不能让队长看见你这个样子
Wait. Wait a minute.
等一下
Wait, don't just say that and walk away.
等下，你不能就这样走了
Talk to me.
我们得谈谈
I had a brother who was an addict,
我的弟弟也是个瘾君子
my baby brother.
亲弟弟
You never told me that.
你之前没跟我说过
So, I can't be around it.
所以我没法再接受另一个这样的人
Not again.
绝对不要
Look, I'm not...
我不是...
You're not?
你不是？
You're not what?
你不是什么？
Not my father.
我和我爸不一样
Do you think I'm my father?
你觉得我们一样么？
I don't care.
我不在乎这个
I have to go to work.
我要去工作了
Hey, so is your brother okay now?
你的弟弟现在好了么？
Bye, Nick.
再见，尼克
If there is one thing I can't stomach, it's self-pity.
这世上只有一件事我不能容忍，那就是自艾自怜者
You,
那个
and you over there.
还有那边那个
I work for the slave traders.
我为工贩工作
Get your rapid refund.
投资回报迅速
I'm a human billboard.
我是人体广告牌
Get your fucking rapid refund.
回报真他妈的迅速啊
I sell my blood, type O.
我卖血，O型
I haven't eaten in three days.
我三天没有吃饭了
And so it goes.
就这么去啦
Valuable blood.
宝贵的血啊
It's frostbite fucking cold out here.
户外已经冷到了极致
I'm losing my left toes due to not taking my shoes off at night.
因为晚上也不能把鞋脱掉，我的左脚趾已经没了知觉
It's all going in the book.
这些都将被我写进书里
My masterpiece,Memoirs of a Moron.
我的另一部杰作，《一个蠢蛋的回忆录》
Are we inside now, or out?
我们现在是在室内还是室外呢？
There is no inside,no outside.
对我来说这已经没什么分别了
I have to go to the bathroom.
我去下厕所
No container,no contained.
没有厕所，甚至连个坑都没有
What's up, old man?
怎么啦，老头？
No birth.
没有出生
What you drinking,anything good?
你喝什么好东西呢？
Got anything for me?
能给我点么？
What? What?
什么？
You think you are so fucking tough, huh? Come here!
你觉得你很厉害？过来！
No death.
就没有死亡
It's a frigging riddle.
这是一个被诅咒的谜语
Hey, welcome. My name is Joey, and I'm an addict.
欢迎，我叫乔伊，我是一个毒瘾患者
Hi, there.Hey, Joey.
你好啊 - 嘿，乔伊
It's good to see everybody here today.
很高兴今天在这里见到大家
And it's really good I'm seeing a number of new faces.
更让我高兴的是有几个新面孔出现
Actually about four or five of you.
大概有4-5个
It's always good to see new people coming into the room.
每次有新人来到这里我们都非常欣慰
At this time,I'd like to let you know
我只说一件事
that we do have free coffee and cookies over there.
那边有免费的咖啡和饼干
And I can testify about the goodness of the cookies.
我可以证明饼干对健康有好处
I baked them myself, they are fantastic.
这是我自己烤的，很不错
At this time, if you have something
如果你们
maybe that you want to talk about,
有什么话想说
something you want to get off your chest,
有什么心事需要人分担
go ahead and raise your hand.We would love to hear from you.
请举手，我们很乐意成为你的倾听者
I was 11 when I got high for the first time,
我第一次吸毒时11岁
and it felt like I was home.
达到兴奋点时我有种回到家的感觉
Well, I woke up one morning in Paris.
某天早上，我在巴黎醒过来
It took me a while to figure out that I was in Paris.
花了好一会儿我才确定自己到了巴黎
And I had completely forgotten that I had
我完全忘了前一天晚上
flown a 747 full of people the night before.
我乘上了一架飞往巴黎，满载乘客的播音747的事
I was out of the hospital no more than three weeks.
我不到三个星期就出院了
And I stayed over my mother's house.
然后一直住在母亲家里
I couldn't take it anymore.
到后来我实在是受不了了
I doused my hand with lighter fluid and lit it on fire
我把火机油浇在手上，点了火
just to get the morphine.
就像卖火柴的小女孩
Go figure.
我想象着吗啡能出现在我的手上
Psst.
呲
I saw your father the other day.
前两天我看到你爸了
He didn't look so good.
他看上去状况不太好
You know my father?
你认识他？
He is a hard guy not to know.
大家都认识他
Thank you.
谢谢
Your old man doesn't look good.
你们家的老头看上去脸色不好
Someone should get him inside.
应该找个人把他接回家
Well, you should get inside.
你也是
We can get you in somewhere.
我知道有个地方你能去
He sleeps in the parking garage, right?
他是不是睡在车库里？
Barlow's garage?
巴洛的车库？
Don't know.
不清楚
The other day Barlow and Ron were giving him a hard time.
前两天巴洛和罗恩给了他一点颜色看
Barlow killed a guy,16 years in Walpole.
巴洛杀过人，在沃波尔蹲了16年
They shouldn't have let him out.
他们就不该放他出来
A guy like that.
一个像他那样的人...
Barlow and Ron lure your old man upstairs...、
巴洛和罗恩把你们家老爷子骗上了楼
Hey, buddy ... to the top floor
嘿伙计... - 骗到了顶层
Let's have a drink.
来喝一杯吧
You want to have a drink with us?
不想和我们喝一杯么？
Said they have a bottle.
说他们有酒
When they get to the top,
一上到顶层
they grab him and hold him over the edge, upside down.
他们就抓住他的脚，把他大头朝下地拎到了栏杆外面
I told you not to come around here no more. This is Barlow's garage.
我告诉过你不要再来这晃悠了，这是我巴洛的车库
This is my garage, bitch!
我的车库，狗娘养的！
He didn't drop him?
他没把他扔下去？
Said next time
他们说那是下次的事
he'll drop him.
再有下次的话，他真会把他扔下去
He's a freaking psycho,Barlow.
巴洛真是个可怕的疯子
The manager kicks you out of this place at 9:15.
店长晚上9点15就把你赶出去
The sign on the door says it doesn't close until 9:30.
可是门上写着9点30才歇业
How can he do that?
他怎么能这样？
Is that legal?
这合法么？
You might want to close that window.
记得把窗户关好
Last week a rat jumped into the van.
上周有只老鼠跑到车里来了
Hey.
嘿
Moses! Moses!
摩斯！摩斯！
Hi, Moses.It's okay.
嗨，摩斯 - 没事
It's Nick, from Harbor Street.
我是尼克，从港湾街来的
You need anything?
需要帮助么？
You want to get in out of the cold?
别在这受冻了
Hey, you haven't seen Jonathan, have you?
嘿，你没看到乔纳桑吧
No, not for weeks.Thank God.
几个礼拜都没看到了，真是谢天谢地
You have to take it outside.
去外面喝
Hey, welcome. My name is Joey, and I'm an addict.
欢迎，我叫乔伊，我是一个毒瘾患者
Hi, Joey.
嗨，乔伊
What the fuck are you doing here? Standing like some ghoul.
你在这做什么鬼？像个食尸鬼似的
You're lucky I realized it was you. Otherwise, bamo!
你该庆幸我把你认出来了，不然的话，砰！
Right. Bamo.
好吧，砰
Are you here in your professional capacity?
你是在发挥你的专业才能么？
Scooping up bodies from the filthy streets
把倒在肮脏街道上的尸体
to carry them to the Harbor Street palace?
都给搬回港湾街的宫殿去
A haven for homos?
那个基佬收容所？
I'm working tonight, yes.
我今晚确实是在上班
Come on.
来吧
Come on, what?
什么来吧？
Come on, it's freezing out here tonight.
上车，外面很冷
Freezing? I don't feel it.
冷？我可没感觉
So, they have come to me with their tails between their legs, huh?
他们终于夹着尾巴来求我回去了，嗯？
You know what I say?
你听到我的话没有？
Fuck them.
去他妈的吧
去他妈的
Up yours, Harbor Street.
去你的港湾街
You are still barred from Harbor Street.
你还在港湾街的禁入期
I think I have been here before.
我想我之前来过这里
Yeah, I was mugged here once by a bunch of mother-raping drug addicts.
上次在这我被一群操娘的小毒罐子给抢了
Thanks, Jeff.
谢谢，杰夫
Good luck.
祝你好运
Christ, don't tell me you live here.
老天啊，别告诉我你就住这儿
A fucking hellhole.
这真他妈的是个老鼠洞
I'll have a vodka screwdriver, please.
来杯螺丝起子
（注：Screwdriver，一种由伏特加和橙汁调和成的鸡尾酒）
There is no liquor here.
这儿没酒
No vodka? No vodka.
- 没有伏特加？ - 没有
No vodka.
没有伏特加
Fine, it's evil shit anyway.
好吧，反正也不是什么好东西
You know, I'm putting some money aside.
我存了些钱
I'm going to get my life back together.
我准备重新开始我的生活
I got a friend in Florida.
我在佛罗里达有个朋友
He's got a job and an apartment,they're waiting for me in St. Petersburg.
他给我准备了一份工作和一间公寓，在圣彼得堡
Right.
是啊
You don't believe me,do you?
你不相信我是吧？
No. No.
不信 - 不信？
That's a terrible thing to say,
真是太让我难过了
you don't believe your own father.
你居然不相信自己的父亲
I'm going upstairs,go to bed.
我上楼睡觉去了
My roommates are away for the weekend.
我室友周末不在
You will be unbarred in a few days,
再过几天你的禁令就解除了
so you can stay here for a bit.
所以在你回港湾街之前
Until you go back to Harbor Street...
你可以在我这呆几天
Oh, no, I'm never going back to that fucking place.
哦，不，我绝对不要再回去那里了
Never.
永远不要
Oh, no.
哦，不
Hey, don't drink in here.
喂，别在这里喝酒
You know, I have been thinking about your beautiful mother
我一直在思考你的漂亮老妈
and her non-accident.
和她那个“非意外”的事
And I have been thinking, why would she do something like that?
我在想，她为什么要那么做呢？
Do you want a drink? No.
喝一口？- 不了
Oh, right. You prefer the other stuff.
哦，好吧，你不喜欢酒
I think I have a problem with both.
我对这两件事都有疑问
A problem?
有疑问？
Oh, I feel for you.
哦，我能感觉到
It must be problematic.
一定不是什么简单的问题
The night she did it,she read something I wrote.
那天晚上，她读了我写的东西
A story, she thought it was about her.
一个故事，他觉得那是在说她
Was it?
是么？
Yes.
确实是
It was about a woman who works two jobs
我写了一个女人，身兼二职
and tries to fit in a couple of hours
并且努力从两份工作的空档中挤出时间
between each to be with her kid.
来陪她的孩子
She works as a bank teller.
她是银行出纳
She works as a waitress.
也是餐厅服务员
She comes home and waits on the kid.
她回家还要带孩子
I wasn't finished with the story.
我没有写完那个故事
I was going to write how the kid appreciated it,
我打算在后面写出那个孩子的感激之情
whatever time she had for him.
不管她陪在他身边的时间是长是短
He didn't think she was a bad mother.
他从来都觉得她是个好妈妈
And he loved her.
他爱她
She was all he had.
她是他的全部
I didn't write that part.
我没有写这个部分
I didn't get that far.
我还没有写到那里
So that's the story you tell
所以这就是你认为的
of why your mother killed herself.
你妈自杀的原因
I haven't told it to anyone.
我从没对任何人说起过这个故事
You tell it to yourself. Those are the best stories.
你对你自己说过，这些故事是最好的
It's a good yarn.
很好的故事
There is only one part that's horseshit.
但有一个相当扯淡的部分
No one kills themselves because they read a story.
没有人会因为读了一个故事而自杀
I don't care how good a writer you are,
无论多么优秀的作家
you can't kill someone with words.
都无法做到单凭文字就扼杀一个生命
I have a theory.
我有一个看法
The reason people commit suicide
那些自杀的人
is because they don't like themselves.
理由无非是他们不爱自己
Self-hatred.
厌恶自己
I think it's a very reasonable explanation. Don't you?
很合理的解释，不是么？
Self-hatred?
自我厌恶？
You're familiar with the concept?
你对这个概念不陌生吧？
Yes.
嗯
Of course,
当然了
maybe the question isn't why she killed herself when she did,
也许问题不在为什么她自杀
but why she chose to stick around as long as she did.
而是她为何要选择活下去
Anyway, my writing is going extremely well.
不管怎么说，我的写作进展相当顺利
The book's classic.
那本书真是一流的
And to answer your previous question, it does exist.
回答一下你先前提出的那个质疑，这本书确实存在
As do you.
你也一样
Why?
为什么？
Because of me. Because I made you.
因为我啊，我生了你
I'm going to go to sleep.
我要去睡觉了
The blanket's on the couch.
毯子在沙发上
Hey!
喂！
Hey! Hold on!
喂！等一下！
Hey.
喂
What are you doing? Where you going?
你干嘛，你要去哪？
Where am I going? I'm going to my suite at The Ritz.
去哪？去我在利兹酒店的套房啊
They are holding one for me just in case I ever want to drop by and use it.
他们有一间永远为我待命的套房呢
I gotta get going. I'll be late for the slave traders,
我得走了，不然上班就来不及了
all the jobs will be taken.
工贩那的临时职位可都很热门呢
Well, are you coming back?
你还回来么？
Coming back where? Here.
回来哪里？ - 这里
Out of curiosity,
出于好奇我得问一下
why have you not ever asked me to stay with you before?
你之前怎么都没叫我留下来过？
I thought if you try and save a drowning man you might go down, too.
我觉得如果你去救一个溺水的人，你也会跟着沉下去的
A drowning man?
溺水的人？
I'm not a drowning man.
我可不是溺水的人
I'm a survivor! An artist!
我是一个生存者，艺术家！
I'm not going to die out here
我可不会死在外头
I'm not your poor sensitive mother! I'm a survivor!
我跟你那敏感的可怜老妈不一样，我是个生存家！
And you know what?
你知道么？
Luckily for you, you are my son, so you are one, too!
成为我的儿子是一大幸事，因为你也将继承生存家的本领
You are not your mother and you are not me, Nicholas Flynn!
你不是你妈，也不是我，尼古拉斯・弗林！
I absolve you!
我现在宣告你为独立的个体！
You are not me. I made you, but you are not me!
你不是我，我生了你，但你和我不同！
I'll see you again.
再会
Yeah.
好吧
A few months after that I left Harbor Street.
几个月后，我离开了港湾街
Yo, it's the man.
呦，是你啊
I'll see you later, man.
待会见
All right. Be good.
好啦，小心点
Yeah.
嗯
All right.
好啦
Hey.
嘿
I'm taking off.
我要走了
Yeah, I heard.
嗯，听说了
Thanks. - For what?
谢啦 - 谢什么？
For nothing.
没有
For the swift kick in the ass.
谢谢你踹醒我的那一脚
You're welcome.
不客气
No more Harbor Street, huh?
不会再回来了吧
I guess not.
我想不会
What about you, you gonna stay here for a while?
你呢，还要再做一段时间？
Yeah. I'm not done yet.
嗯，我的事还很多
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
我只想说声对不起
For what?
对不起什么？
About your brother.
你弟弟的事
Oh.
哦
Thank you.
谢谢
Take care of yourself.
保重啊
You, too.
你也是
I go back to school,
我回到学校
finish my undergraduate degree, get my diploma.
读完了落下的本科课程，拿到了文凭
I take a poetry workshop.
我加入了一间诗作研究会
I work in Harlem and Crown Heights and the South Bronx, teaching.
我在开始哈伦区，皇冠高地和南布朗克斯区的几所学校任教
In some schools, half the kids I work with live in shelters.
某几所学校里半数的学生都住在收容所里
So, when Lucille Clifton says, "Her eyes are animals," what is that?
所以，露西尔・克利夫顿的这句诗“她的双眸是跳跃的生灵”，我们把它称为一种？
（注：露西尔・克利夫顿，黑人女性，马里兰州桂冠诗人）
An image.
意象
Good, but what kind of image?
很好，但具体是什么意象呢？
A metaphor.
象征性意象
And what do you think she is trying to say about her eyes?
你们觉得她想借助眼睛来表达什么呢？
My father's letters follow me.
父亲仍然在给我寄信
Nicky Nu-nu,you will be happy to know
尼克小宝贝，
my writing is doing extraordinarily well.
我的写作进展十分顺利
Soon, very soon,I shall be known.
很快，无需时日，我将为世人所知
Within a year,Jonathan qualifies for
过了不到一年的时间，乔纳桑成功地申请到了一所公寓
an apartment, Section 8, subsidized.
中央八区，政府补贴
Unbeknownst to me,some strings have been
但我不知道的是，在申请过程中
pulled by people I once worked with.
我以前的同事们帮了不少的忙
Yeah?
来了
It's Nick.
我是尼克
Nick who?
尼克什么？
Nicky Nu-nu.
尼克小宝贝儿
Oh.
哦
Nicky Nu-nu.
尼克小宝贝
Just want to make sure it's you.
再确认一下
You never know what lurks in this neighborhood.
你不知道有多少怪人在这个街区转悠
How are you?
你还好吧？
Shake my hand properly.Give me a firm handshake.
来，好好握一下手，用力
That's better.
好多了
Don't break it.
别把我手弄断了
You're dressed,that's good.
你这次穿着衣服呢，挺好的
Well, the place is nice.
这里不错啊
Yeah.
是啊
This is my little paradise.
我的小天堂
My little oasis.
小绿洲
My little home away from
远离我那所小房子的...
my little home.
小房子
Well, I'm impressed.
真是难以置信
I'm very tranquil,I'm peaceful...
晚来寂静，一派平和
Pretty soon he launches into a familiar flurry of hate speech.
很快他又开始义愤填膺地大放陈词
...young girls being raped,day and night,
...每天都有年轻女孩被强奸
by these bastards,these pederasts,
被那些无良混蛋，邪教徒
these fucking priests,these cretins, these homos.
道貌岸然的牧师，白痴，同性恋者
Believe me,I know all about it.
相信我，我什么都知道
I wasn't locked up in federal prison with choirboys, kiddo.
我当时可没有跟唱诗班的男孩一起被关在联邦监狱里，小子
Interstate transportation of stolen securities,
跨洲运送窃取所得有价证券罪
that was the charge.
这才是真正的指控罪名
The checking business brought to you by the great Dippity-Do Doyle.
这单生意是老滑头Doyle让我接的
If I didn't do what he said, he would have killed you and your mother.
如果我不按他说的做，他早就把你和你老妈给杀了
Believe me, kiddo.
相信我，小子
I have trouble focusing,
我无法集中精神
I consider leaving quickly,
我有点想尽快离开
but I will myself to stay.
但最终我强迫自己留下来
My job was to enter the banks and open an account.
我要做的就是到银行开户
I was the only one able to finesse my way in.
我可是唯一一个能做得神不知鬼不觉的人
The secret? The secret?
秘诀就是
Always go to a female teller.
永远去女出纳员负责的柜台
A black? Forget about the fucking blacks. Low fucking morale.
黑人？别提操蛋的黑人了，那些人一点道德都没有
Go to them? I couldn't get on fucking first base with a black teller.
去他们的柜台？那我一定连第一步都达成不了
It's early in the month, so he hasn't gone through his disability check yet.
现在还是月初，这表示他才刚刚拿到政府补贴
This means he has been drinking.
他一定会去喝酒
...good Russian vodka. Not that rotgut crap.
...上好的黑伏特加，可不是那种掺水的垃圾
Want some?
来点？
Uh, no thanks.
呃，不了谢谢
New teeth?
补牙了？
Huh?
哈？
You got some new teeth. - Yep.
你去补牙了 - 是啊
Courtesy of Uncle Sam.Best dentist in the world.
那可真是世界上最好的牙医诊所
Looks nice.
看上去不错
Here, I brought you something.
给你，我给你带了点东西
What the hell is this?
这是什么东西？
It's a book of poems.
一本诗集
Poems.
诗
I wrote it.
我的作品
Actually, it's getting an award.
事实上，它有可能会获奖
An award, from whom?
奖？哪的奖？
From Pen. - Pen.
（注：PEN/Voelcker Award for Poetry，美国一诗作类文学奖）
Are they giving you a pen?
他们会奖励你一根笔么？
Is it dedicated to me?
这本书是献给我的么？
No. No?
不是 - 不是？
Am I in it?
里头提到我了么？
There are some poems that refer to you.
有几首诗是以你为参考的
Oh. Let's see.
哦，让我看看
"I'll bend each finger back Until the bottle falls
“我将攥紧每一根手指/直到酒瓶落下
"Until the bone snaps
“骨节折断
"Save him by destroying his hands"
“毁掉他的双手/予他救赎
Do I detect a touch of hostility?
我好像从文字里嗅到了敌意？
I'm doing a reading of it tonight at a book store.
我今晚在书店开朗读会
You can come,if you would like to.
如果你想来的话也可以
All right, all right.
好吧，好吧
I'm going to let you read it.
我现在给你看看这个
Your book? Yeah, The Button Man,
你的书？ - 对，《纽扣人》
also known as The Confessions of Christopher Cobb.
又作《克里斯托弗・柯布的自白书》
You mean it actually exists?
这东西还真的存在啊？
Of course it exists.
当然了
Where the fuck is it?
跑哪去了？
It's somewhere here.
就在这房间的某个地方
Give me a hand here, look in these boxes. Look for a blue folder.
搭把手，去那些箱子里找一个蓝色的文件夹
I think I may have it here.
我记得是在这儿
Yeah. This is it.
没错，这就是了
Here it is, part one.
给你，第一部分
This is part one? How many parts are there?
只是第一部分？总共有多少个？
12. Eight are in existence.
12个，我已经写了8个部分
"Clink, clank, clunk.I think that I am drunk."
“叮，铛，咚，我想我已经醉了。”
Don't read it here, for Christ's sake. That part's a musical.
哦天啊，这里别用念的，它应该被唱出来
I will read it right away and get it back to you.
我读完就还给你
Don't steal anything.
可别偷走什么啊
I promise.
保证不会
I read his book in one afternoon.
某天下午我把它读完了
It's a masterpiece.
真是一流的杰作
I read your poems.
我读了你的诗
That one about the gun is heavy.
关于枪的那首有点沉重
Of course it's an inherited quality.
当然啦，既然遗传了我的才能，品质自然有保证
If you didn't write well,I would be surprised.
如果你写得很差，那我才会吃惊呢
For 30 pages it shows promise.
前30面给人以相当高的期待值
Then like his life,it soon falls apart
紧接着，就像他的人生那样，行文的骨架彻底被打散了
and dissipates into incoherence.
他开始语无伦次
His manuscript is incomplete.
他的书稿是不完整的
As far as I can tell,
我只能说
the only completed book about my father
完成这唯一一本相对完备的关于我父亲的书的
would be the book that fell to me to write.
重任就此落在了我的肩上
Me, my father's un-credited, uncompliant ghost writer.
我，一名永无怨言，无名无分，隶属于我父亲的影子写手
I've been in touch with Little Brown.
我和小布朗取得了联系
They are doing my book. Four million dollars in advance.
他们正在编辑我的书，预付给我四百万美元
Little Brown said my book's a masterpiece.
小布朗说我的书是杰作
Everything I write is a masterpiece.
当然，我书写的一切皆为杰作
"The eyes of the action hero cut from the poster
“从海报上剪下的/英雄的双眼
"All that concrete pressing down
“重重的水泥压下
"A fine edge gleams around your body
“你的身体闪烁着清晰的边界
"As if it could be contained
“似要张开双臂将其容纳
"The way each finger is licked,dipped in and rubbed across the gums
“好似在牙龈上轻拭
"Until the teeth go away
“陪伴直至牙齿脱落的每根手指
"Even my hands kiss you
“我愿以手吻你
"A night broken down into grains
“让暗夜破碎成谷粒
"If you find yourself lost, dig
“如果你迷失方向，快
"A cave in the snow, quickly
“在雪中掘出存身的洞窟
"You need shelter against the night
“你需要庇护以对抗漫漫长夜
"A candle could keep you alive
“一支蜡烛可挽留你的生命
"The engine of your lungs will heat the air around you
“让你的肺叶运转/以加热四下的空气
"Someone will miss you
“某些思念你的人
"They will send out dogs
“将派出援救的犬
"You must be somewhere,right?"
“你一定就在某处，对吗？”
Thank you.
谢谢
There you go.
给你
Thanks.Thanks for coming.
谢谢，谢谢捧场
Hey. - Hey.
嘿 - 嘿
Uh, he's here.
呃，他来了
Jonathan, this is Inez.Inez, this is Jonathan.
乔纳桑，这是伊内兹。伊内兹，这是乔纳桑
A very great pleasure.
很高兴见到你
It's good to meet you.
我也是
And this is Maeve,your granddaughter.
这是玛芙，你的孙女
Would you like to hold her?
想要抱抱她么？
Uh, that's okay.
呃，算了吧
No, he can hold her.
没关系，他可以的
I have held babies before, Nicholas.
我又不是没抱过小孩，尼古拉斯
See?
看到没？
看到了吧？
See?
看到没？
Yeah, I see.
是啊，我看到了
All right, Nicholas,you can have it.
好了，尼古拉斯，你可以留下我的手稿
I bequeath it to you.
我授予你继承的权力
You have the last word.
结尾就拜托你了
[ ※ BGM: Let it Rain - Badly Drawn Boy ]
翻译/时间轴校准:CharlesChouBlues